The Dawn Wall is a documentary, adventure film directed by Peter Mortimer.
The definitive film on the climb that captured
headlines and ignited imaginations worldwide.
Tommy Caldwell and Kevin Jorgeson ascend the hardest big wall of all time: a 19 day ascent of The
Dawn Wall, on the 3,000 foot vertical face of El Capitan, in Yosemite National Park.
The film travels deeper than the climb, digging into the history of the climbers and painting an intimate portrait of
Caldwell's harrowing life experiences that culminated in a single-minded drive to complete this impossible climb.
The Dawn Wall is a heart-warming and inspiring movie that celebrates perseverance,
camaraderie, and the universal spirit of dreaming big, and never giving up.
Self, played by Tommy Caldwell.
Self, played by John Branch.
Self, played by Kevin Jorgeson.
Self, played by Beth Rodden.
Self, played by Becca Pietsch.
The Dawn Wall is a 2017 American-Austrian documentary film directed by Josh Lowell and Peter Mortimer about Tommy Caldwell and Kevin Jorgeson's successful attempt to create the first-ever big wall free climbing route—which they christened The Dawn Wall—on the
historic southeast face (The Wall of Early Morning Light) of El Capitan in Yosemite National Park, which had hitherto only been ascended by aid climbing techniques first pioneered by Warren Harding who made the first aided ascent of the face in 1970.
The film explores themes of based on true story,
climbing, yosemite, rock climbing, el capitan.
The tone is uplifting and thought_provoking.